Joe Teibel

721 E 21st PI, The Dalles, Oregon 97058, joeteibel@gmail.com, 541.760.1978

Team management

More than twenty years in the software industry, the last seven managing engineers and driving product strategy and architecture. Modern software product development and team management practices have led to high performing teams that have delivered company and team success.

Professional experience

- Product development, tech team leadership, people management
- Web & UI/UX development, cloud operations, SaaS products, APIs & microservices
- Architected and built dozens of backend and frontend applications

Work history

Head of Product and Engineering, SketchDeck, 2017-current

SketchDeck was a YCombinator startup, acquired by 24/7 staffing in spring 2023. We use a web application built on Angular and Node to power our graphic design business. Responsible for managing the application development team, collaborating with stakeholders, designers and other company leaders to build and align the software product with our business strategy.

Senior Software Engineer, Nike, 2016-2017

Software engineer team lead on a business and system metrics platform solution to enable a wide range of Nike applications. Instrumental in driving the first release of the platform and developing the long-term vision for the team.

Software Engineer, Hewlett-Packard Company, 2009-2016

Architect and technical lead with a team of engineers on several R&D projects including: software solutions for a book micro-production system, desktop application for leveraging the browser as a UI to deliver print content, web services to power printer apps, web services as a part of a cloud-based publishing platform, and custom cloud-based search engine auth proxy and big-data systems design.

Software Engineer, Knife Edge Software, 2004-2009

Feature level design and implementation for a Windows based aircraft simulator (RealFlight) distributed worldwide. The simulator was developed using C++ across numerous major and minor releases.

Education

Oregon State University, Corvallis, Oregon Masters in Business Administration Graduated June 2017

Oregon Institute of Technology, Klamath Falls, Oregon Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering Minor, Mathematics Graduated June 2004

Personal

You can read a lot more about the projects I've worked on, in story form here: http://www.semanticjudo.com/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joe-teibel-407893156/

Github: https://github.com/junosw